Privacy Policy
==============

[](https://www.linkedin.com/shareArticle?mini=true&url=https://thelazyleader.co/privacy-policy/&title=Privacy%20Policy&summary=Privacy%20Policy "Share on Linkedin")[\[email protected\]](https://thelazyleader.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Your privacy is important to us. It is the Lazy Leader’s policy to respect your privacy and comply with any applicable law and regulation regarding any personal information we may collect about you.

Accordingly:

* we do not sell your data,
* we do not track you,
* we neither use third-party trackers nor third-party cookies, except for a strictly necessary third-party cookie used for fraud prevention purposes (see our [cookie policy](https://thelazyleader.co/cookie-policy/#necessary-cookies) for more information) with our website.

TL;DR
-----

When you log in to our website, you need to use an email and a password. Names or nicknames are optional. Password verification relies on a cryptographic hash of your password, which is stored in our database using the [Bcrypt](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bcrypt?ref=thelazyleader.co) algorithm. When cancelling your account, we delete your data in our database, so you cannot recover your account. Deleting a user is irreversible and will delete all data (including post content) associated with the user.

Except for a strictly necessary cookie, which is set for fraud prevention purposes, we only use first party cookies. We use these cookies to store your login information and site preferences, e.g., when you change the page layout or theme.

A cookie is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the site again, the cookie allows that site to recognize your browser. Cookies store user preferences and other information.

You can configure your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a website attempts to set a cookie.

If you do not wish to accept cookies from us, you should instruct your browser to refuse cookies from [https://thelazyleader.co](https://thelazyleader.co/). In such a case, this will affect your login attempts, and we will be unable to provide you with some of your desired content and services.

Our site contains links to third-party websites and services, and those sites and services have their privacy policies. After following a link to third-party content or services, you should read their privacy policy to understand how they collect and use personal information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any of your activities after you leave our site.

This policy is effective as of 13 May 2021.

Last updated: **8 November 2022**.

Information We Collect
----------------------

Personal information is any information about you which can be used to identify you. This includes information about you as a person such as name, address, your devices, and even information about how you use a website or online service.

Information we collect falls into one of two categories: “voluntarily provided” information and “automatically collected” information.

Voluntarily provided information refers to any information you knowingly and actively provide us when using or participating in any of our services.

Automatically collected information refers to any information sent by your device as a matter of course when using our services.

### Log data

When you visit this website, servers automatically log the standard data provided by your web browser. This includes your device’s Internet Protocol (IP) address, your browser type and version, the pages you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on each page, and other details about your visit.

Additionally, if you encounter certain errors while using the site, data about the error and the circumstances of its occurrence is collected. This data includes your user ID, what you were attempting to do when the error happened, and other technical information relating to the problem. You may or may not receive notice of such errors, even as they occur, or that they have occurred, or the nature of the error.

Please bear in mind that while this information cannot identify you by itself, it may be possible to combine it with other data to identify individual persons.

### Device data

When you visit our website or interact with our services, we collect data about your device, such as:

* device type, i.e., desktop, laptop, mobile, or tablet,
* IP address, and
* geolocation data, i.e., country of origin, if available.

Data we collect can depend on the individual settings of your device and software. We recommend checking the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider to learn what information they make available to us.

### Personal information

We currently collect and process the following minimal personal information. For example, when you subscribe to our newsletter or when you contact us, which includes one or more of the following:

* name or nickname
* email address,
* country of origin (based on your geolocation), and
* social media profile or website and a biographical sketch or outline (for [guest bloggers](https://thelazyleader.co/call-for-guest-bloggers/) only.)

Legitimate Reasons For Processing Your Personal Information
-----------------------------------------------------------

We only collect and use your personal information when we have a legitimate reason for doing so. In which instance we only collect personal information that is reasonably necessary to provide our services to you.

### Collection and use of information

Most of the personal information provided directly by you is processed for one of the following reasons:

* register for an account,
* sign up to receive updates from us via email,
* use a mobile device or web browser to access our content,
* contact us via email, contact form, social media, or on any similar technologies, and
* make a guest post submission.

We collect, hold, use and disclose information for the following purposes. However, personal information will not be further processed in a manner that is incompatible with these purposes:

* to provide you with our platform’s core features and services,
* to enable you to customize or personalize your experience of our website,
* to deliver services to you,
* to contact and communicate with you,
* to enable you to access and use our website,
* for internal record keeping and administrative purposes,
* to attribute any content, e.g., posts and comments, you submit that are published on our website, and
* to provide you with news, special offers and general information about other services which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about, unless you have opted not to receive such information.

### Security of your personal information

When we collect and process personal information, and while we retain this information, we will protect it within commercially acceptable means to prevent loss and theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification.

Although we will do our best to protect the personal information you provide to us, we advise that no method of electronic transmission or storage is 100% secure and no one can guarantee absolute data security.

You are responsible for selecting any password and its overall security strength, ensuring the security of your information within the bounds of our services. For example, ensuring any passwords associated with accessing your personal information and accounts are secure and confidential.

### How long we keep your personal information

We keep your personal information only for as long as we need to. This period depends on what we are using your information for, in accordance with this privacy policy. For example, if you have provided us with personal information as part of creating an account with us, we retain this information for the duration your account exists on our system. If you no longer need an account, we will delete it by removing all details that identify you.

However, if necessary, we may retain your personal information for our compliance with a legal, accounting, or reporting obligation or for archiving purposes.

### Children’s privacy

We do not aim any of our products or services directly at children under the age of 18, and we do not knowingly collect personal information about children under 18.

Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties
---------------------------------------------------

We will disclose personal information to:

* specified third-party service providers to enable them to provide their services including without limitation IT service providers, data storage, hosting and server providers, and payment systems operators, and
* courts, tribunals, regulatory authorities, and law enforcement officers, as required by law, in connection with any actual or prospective legal proceedings, or to establish, exercise, or defend our legal rights.

We use [Hetzner](https://www.hetzner.com/?ref=thelazyleader.co) secured data centres located exclusively in Germany to host our services, including the [Ghost](https://ghost.org/?ref=thelazyleader.co) publishing platform and [Plausible](https://plausible.io/?ref=thelazyleader.co) analytics.

The third parties we use are:

**Buy Me a Coffee**: We use the Buy Me a Coffee crowdfunding service to accept support from our audience and to share content. This optional service processes payments using Stripe (see below.) We do not store or collect your payment card details. For more information, read their Privacy Policy at [https://www.buymeacoffee.com/privacy-policy](https://www.buymeacoffee.com/privacy-policy?ref=thelazyleader.co).

**form.taxi**: Our contact forms use a privacy-focused form submission and email service called form.taxi. When using this service, personal information provided directly by you includes name or nickname, email address and message content. form.taxi use Mailgun secured data centres located exclusively in the European Union to process the data provided for transmitting emails. For more information, read their Privacy Policy at [https://form.taxi/en/privacy](https://form.taxi/en/privacy?ref=thelazyleader.co).

**Mailgun**: We use a transactional email service to send, receive, and monitor email open rates of messages sent to you using Mailgun. We use Mailgun secured data centres located exclusively in the European Union to process the data provided for transmitting emails. For more information, please refer to Mailgun’s privacy policy at: [https://www.mailjet.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.mailjet.de/privacy-policy/?ref=thelazyleader.co).

**Stripe:** We provide paid services and use a third-party payment processing service called Stripe. We do not store or collect your payment card details. Our third-party payment processor receives this information directly and adheres to the standards set by the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard. The PCI-DSS is managed by the [PCI Security Standards Council](https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/?ref=thelazyleader.co), which is a joint effort of brands including Visa, Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information. Stripe’s Privacy Policy can be viewed at [https://stripe.com/gb/privacy](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy?ref=thelazyleader.co), and differs [depending on your country](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy?ref=thelazyleader.co#controllers-and-jurisdiction-specific-provisions).

International Transfers of Personal Information
-----------------------------------------------

We store and process the personal information we collect in the United Kingdom, or where we or our partners, affiliates, and third-party providers maintain facilities.

The countries to which we store, process, or transfer your personal information may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. If we transfer your personal information to third parties in other countries: (i) we will perform those transfers in accordance with the requirements of applicable law, and (ii) we will protect the transferred personal information in accordance with this privacy policy.

Your Rights and Controlling Your Personal Information
-----------------------------------------------------

**Your choice**: By providing personal information to us, you understand we will collect, hold, use, and disclose your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy. You do not have to provide personal information to us. However, if you do not, it will affect your use of our website or the products and services offered.

**Information from third parties**: If we receive personal information about you from a third party, we will protect it as set out in this privacy policy. If you are a third party providing personal information about somebody else, you represent and warrant that you have such person’s consent to provide the personal information to us.

**Access**: You can request details of the personal information that we hold about you.

**Correction**: If you believe that any information we hold about you is inaccurate, out of date, incomplete, irrelevant, or misleading, please contact us using the details provided in this privacy policy. We will take reasonable steps to correct any information found to be inaccurate, incomplete, misleading, or out of date.

**Non-discrimination**: We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your rights over your personal information. Unless we need your personal information to provide you with a particular service or offer, for example providing user support, we will not deny you services or charge you different prices or rates for services. This includes discounts and other benefits, or imposing penalties, or providing you with a different level or quality of services.

**Notification of data breaches**: We will comply with laws applicable to us relating to any data breach.

**Complaints:** If you believe we have breached the law relating to data protection, and wish to make a complaint, please contact us using the details below and provide us with full details of the alleged breach. We will promptly investigate your complaint and respond to you, in writing, setting out the outcome of our investigation and the steps we will take to deal with your complaint. You also have the right to contact the United Kingdom [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/?ref=thelazyleader.co) (ICO) about your complaint.

**Unsubscribe**: To unsubscribe from our email database or opt-out of communications, please contact us using the details provided in this privacy policy, or opt-out using the opt-out facilities provided in the communication.

Use of Cookies
--------------

We use minimal “cookies” to collect information about you and your activity across our site. A cookie is a small piece of data that our website stores on your computer, and accesses each time you visit. This helps us serve you content based on preferences you have specified.

Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://thelazyleader.co/cookie-policy/) for more information.

Business Transfers
------------------

If another party acquires the Lazy Leader and our assets, or in the unlikely event that we cease trading, we would include data, including your personal information, among the assets transferred to any parties who acquire us. You acknowledge that such transfers can occur, and that any parties who acquire us may, to the extent permitted by applicable law, continue to use your personal information according to this policy. However, they will be required to adopt this policy as the basis for any ownership or use rights we have over such information.

Limits of Our Policy
--------------------

Our site contains links to third-party website and services that are not operated by us. It is worth noting those websites and services have their privacy policies, and we cannot accept responsibility or liability for their respective privacy practices.

After following a link to third-party content or services, you should read their privacy policy to understand how they collect and use personal information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any of your activities after you leave our site.

### Changes to this policy

At our discretion, we can change our privacy policy to reflect updates to our business processes, current acceptable practices, or legislative or regulatory changes. If we decide to change this privacy policy, we will post the changes here at the same link by which you are accessing this privacy policy.

When the changes are significant, or required by applicable law, we will contact you (based on your selected preferences for communications from us) and all our registered users with the new details and links to the updated or changed policy.

If required by law, we will get your permission or give you the opportunity to opt in to or opt out of, as applicable, any new uses of your personal information.

Additional Disclosures For General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) Compliance (EU)
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

### Data controller / data processor

The GDPR distinguishes between organizations that process personal information for their purposes (known as “data controllers”) and organizations that process personal information on behalf of other organizations (known as “data processors”). We, the Lazy Leader, located at the address provided in the Contact Us section of this Privacy Policy, are a Data Controller regarding the personal information you provide to us.

### Legal bases for processing your personal information

We will only collect and use your personal information when we have a legal right to do so. In which case, we will collect and use your personal information lawfully, fairly and transparently. If we seek your consent to process your personal information, and you are under 16 years of age, we will seek your parent or legal guardian’s consent to process your personal information for that specific purpose.

Our lawful bases depend on the services you use and how you use them. This means we only collect and use your information on the following grounds:

### Consent from you

Where you give us consent to collect and use your personal information for a specific purpose. You may withdraw your consent at any time using the facilities we provide; however, this will not affect any use of your information that has already taken place. You may consent to provide your email address for receiving emails from us. While you can unsubscribe at any time, we cannot recall any email we have already sent. If you have any further enquiries about how to withdraw your consent, please feel free to enquire using the details provided in the Contact Us section of this privacy policy.

### Performance of a contract or transaction

Where you have entered into a contract or transaction with us, or to take preparatory steps before our entering into a contract or transaction with you. For example, if you contact us with an enquiry, we require personal information such as your name and contact details to respond.

### Our Legitimate Interests

Where we assess it is necessary for our legitimate interests, such as for us to provide, operate, improve and communicate our services. We consider our legitimate interests to include research and development, understanding our audience, marketing and promoting our services, measures taken to operate our services efficiently, marketing analysis, and measures taken to protect our legal rights and interests.

### Compliance with law

In some cases, we may have a legal obligation to use or keep your personal information. Such cases may include, but are not limited to, court orders, criminal investigations, government requests, and regulatory obligations. If you have any further enquiries about how we retain personal information to comply with the law, please feel free to enquire using the details provided in the Contact Us section of this privacy policy.

### International transfers outside the European Economic Area (EEA)

We will ensure that any transfer of personal information from countries in the European Economic Area (EEA) to countries outside the EEA will be protected by appropriate safeguards. For example, by using standard data protection clauses approved by the ICO.

Your Rights and Controlling Your Personal Information
-----------------------------------------------------

**Restrict**: You are entitled to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information if: (i) you are concerned about the accuracy of your personal information, (ii) you believe we may have unlawfully processed your personal information, (iii) you need us to maintain the personal information solely for a legal claim, or (iv) we are in the process of considering your objection relating to processing because of legitimate interests.

**Objecting to processing**: You are entitled to object to processing of your personal information that is based on our legitimate interests or public interest. If this is done, we must provide compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which overrides your interests, rights, and freedoms, to proceed with the processing of your personal information.

**Data portability**: You may have the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you. Where possible, we will provide this information in an easily readable machine format. You may also have the right to request that we transfer this personal information to a third party.

**Deletion**: You have a right to request that we delete the personal information we hold about you at any time, and we will take reasonable steps to delete your personal information from our current records. If you ask us to delete your personal information, we will let you know how the deletion affects your use of our website or products and services. There may be exceptions to this right for specific legal reasons which, if applicable, we will set out when responding to your request. If you terminate or delete your account, we will delete your personal information within 30 days of the deletion of your account. It is worth noting that search engines and similar third parties may retain copies of your publicly available personal information. For example, certain profile information and public comments, even after you have deleted the information from our services or deactivated your account.

Contact Us
----------

For any questions or concerns regarding your privacy, you can contact us using the following details:

Published by

I created the Lazy Leader for everyone who is starting their leadership journey. Join me as I share my experiences and promote leadership development and the pursuit of productive laziness.
